# 你看看这样一刮就下来了
You see you can scrape it off like this
# 真白
It's so white
# 萝卜丝鲫鱼汤
"Ji Yu" Carp and Shredded Radish Soup
# 你看我打鳞的时候也没打的那么干净
You see I didn't scale it so clean
# 为什么 还有个小处理
Why? Because there is another step to do
# 这鱼上边有很多黑膜
Many black membranes on the skin of the fish
# 熬出这汤是灰的 咱们处理一下
The fish soup cooked with it will be grey, so we will handle it
# 开开的水 小窍门
Tip: with boiling water
# 先烫鱼头
Scald it from the head
# 再烫鱼尾
then the tail
# 你看一烫它就变色 发白了吧
You see it turns white after scalding it
# 翻一身儿
turn it over
# 再烫这头
scald this side in the same way
# 今天这好 现买的活鱼
Today we prepared live fish
# 刚才蹦蹦蹦直跳呢 马上冲凉
It was still jumping just now; Wash it immediately with cold water
# 你看看 这样一刮就下来了
You see it is easy to scrape it off
# 因为要赶快冲凉
It must be washed at once
# 因为这鱼你烫大了也不行
Because too much scalding won't work either
# 烫大了这皮破了
Too much scalding will break its skin
# 所以瞬间要给它冲凉
So rinse it immediately
# 说这鱼的汤有土腥味是哪儿啊
Which part causes the a gamey taste in the soup?
# 发苦 土腥味大 你看这黑膜
Bitter and gamey. Look at these black membranes
# 这得拿手都给处理干净
All of them should be removed by hand
# 更重要的一点 这个鱼鳍
More importantly, the fin
# 划水 尾边的摆水  前面的鳍
Those for paddling at the tail, and the front fins
# 都得给弄干净了 为什么呢
Should be cleaned up, why?
# 不弄干净它腥啊 上边（有）粘液
Because it is fishy, there is a lot of mucus on it
# 你看照这边 看干净吧
Look at this side, how clean!
# 颜色也好看了
The color looks better, too
# 那会儿煲出那汤来 倍儿白
The soup that we cook later will be quite white
# 两条
Two fish
# 你看我们这个辅料是什么
Look at our other ingredients
# 海米用开水泡上 先洗干净后泡
Clean some dried shrimps then soak them in boiled water
# 这水要要的
Keep the water
# 葱 姜 香菜 处理的还行吧
Green onion, ginger and cilantro, not bad, right?
# 这炖出这汤倍儿白
The soup will be particularly white
# 萝卜丝鲫鱼汤
"Ji Yu" Carp and Shredded Radish Soup
# 这也是淮扬菜的老菜
It is also a typical Huaiyang dish
# 这是淮扬菜啊
Is this Huaiyang cuisine?
# 瞧瞧 这大爷
Look at our chef, Da Ye
# 点火
Turn on the stove
# 这个锅一定要烧热
The wok must be hot
# 我们常说的叫热锅凉油
This is what we often say "hot wok and cold oil"
# 但是鲫鱼汤要好
But if you want the soup to be tasty
# 原本的最传统的搁点大油
The most traditional method should have used lard
# 出来这汤还白的
that soup should be more white
# 油温得热一点儿
The oil temperature should be a little higher
# 大妈稍微远一点
Da Ma, keep away a little
# 这个鱼不用腌
The fish don't need to be marinated
# 不用动它啊 别动它一动皮破了
Don't touch it, or its skin will break
# 没搁多少油就是煎
Didn't put too much oil in it. Just frying it
# 翻身了 再翻一下
Flip it over. Flip it again
# 皮也没破吧 前期处理的好
The skin is not broken, because we did a good preparation
# 这时候我们要把葱姜随手就放进去了
Now, add the spring onions and ginger
# 就可以了
That's it
# 放水（热水） 大火
Put water (hot water) in it, high heat
# 黄酒 海米
Huangjiu rice wine, small dried shrimps
# 这得炖多长时间
How long does it need to be stewed?
# 应该说是在一刻钟到二十分钟
It should be stewed for 15-20 mins
# 说去腥的方法很多 搁上几粒花椒
Speaking of removing the fishy smell, there are many ways. Put a few Sichuan peppercorns
# 开了 这个就用大火煮 大火熬鱼炖鱼
It’s boiling. It should be cooked with high heat for braising fish, stewing fish
# 为什么要把那汤给没过鱼了
Why is soup over the fish?
# 它得炖一会儿
It has to be stewed for a while
# 把它移到这火 同时进行
Move it to this burner, cook together on both sides
# 胡椒 白胡椒
Pepper, White pepper
# 盐待会再放
Salt will be put it in later
# 盐早放它这个鱼就不爱烂
If we put salt too early, the fish won't be soft and tender
# 出白汤的就慢 行 这个先慢慢炖着
So that the soup turns white slower. Ok. Let it stew slowly
# 锅热了 这油不用要太多
The wok is hot. Don’t need too much oil
# 炒萝卜丝 去萝卜的臭味
Fry shredded radish to remove the radish smell
# 你看再照照那个
You film that again
# 那有点要白吧 白了已经起白了
It's turning white. It's white already
# 一放萝卜还白
It will be whiter after putting radish in
# （萝卜丝）就是煸煸 花椒煸出味来就行
Slightly fry it (shredded radish), as long as the aroma of Sichuan peppercorn comes out
# 搁点水
Put in some water
# 这个还是要这样大的火
Cooking still with this high heat
# 这还要处理一下 把这浮沫给打出来
This needs to be done, skim off the scum
# 一会它一开锅还有沫子呢
Later, there will be more scum when it boils
# 那沫子是油沫
That scum is oil.
# 把那油给打干净 这萝卜丝就没有臭味了
Skim off all the oil then, so there will not be any smell in the radish
# 我做这个就特别拿手
I’m very good at making this soup
# 原来在饭店的时候 有些老领导
When I worked at restaurant, there were some honored guests
# 就爱吃大爷这个萝卜丝鲫鱼汤
who loved to have Da Ye’s Ji Yu Carp and Shredded Radish Soup
# 一种方式就是喝汤
One of the ways to have it is to drink the soup only
# 再一种方式在这也跟网友说一声
There's another way that I’d like to tell our audience
# 想吃鱼 别吃鲫鱼 买条鳜鱼
If you want to eat fish, don’t eat ji yu carp. Buy a Chinese perch
# 鳜鱼片成片 在这锅里边一烫
Cut the Chinese perch into slices, and cook them quickly in the wok
# 鳜鱼的鱼片 汤必须是鲫鱼的
Chinese perch fish slices, which must be cooked in ji yu carp soup
# 萝卜丝已经好了 咱把它捞出来
Shredded radish is ready, let’s take them out
# 捞到这里头 继续滚
Take them into here, keep boiling
# 换成那边 关火
Move to that side, turn off the heat
# 你看更白了
You see it’s more white
# 这汤白了这火稍微小一点
The soup is white, turn the heat down a little
# 因为火大就是要翻这个汤要白
Because high heat is for boiling the soup to white
# 白了以后就不要再大了
When it has turned white, no need to use high heat
# 就时候二次调味 盐
Now second time seasoning, salt
# 还搁什么啊 什么都不搁了
Anything else to put in? Nothing
# 味精都不搁 你看一会你喝吧
No MSG even, you just taste it later
# 这个萝卜丝到什么程度 入口要即化
How much do we cook the shredded radish? Till it could melt in your mouth
# 大爷先吃了
Da Ye is having it first
# 盛到砂锅里头
Put it into a claypot
# 葱姜拣干净
Pick onion and ginger out
# 香菜 真好
Cilantro, very good
# 展示一下成品
Show us the finished dish
# 你瞧瞧
You see
# 大爷真稳当
Da Ye is so steady